Guide to the Tamiment Library (Labor and the Left) Web Archive: Environmentalism / Green Movement Web Archive TAM.619
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library (Labor and the Left) Web Archive: Environmentalism / Green Movement Web Archive
2008-
TAM.619
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Environmentalism / Green Movement, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library, which was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived web sites of entities concerned with environmental issues, and that reflect a left/progressive viewpoint. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Environmentalism / Green Movement collection contains periodically archived web sites of entities concerned with these issues and that reflect a left/progressive viewpoint. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library (Labor and the Left) Web Archive: Environmentalism / Green Movement Web Archive was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
Related Archival Materials
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the web page Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Environmentalists |z United States.; Green movement |z United States.
- Environmentalism and Green Movements, 2009-
  - 350.org, 7/13/2011-
  - ARISE! Social Network for Climate Activism, 10/7/2011-
  - BlueGreen Alliance, 1/07/2012-
  - Climate and Capitalism: An Ecosocialist Journal, 5/14/2012-
  - Climate Crisis Coalition, 5/5/2012-
  - Climate Pledge of Resistance, 3/23/2010-
  - Earth First! Worldwide, 8/16/2009-
  - Ecoprisoners, 5/11/2012-
  - Frack Action, 7/5/2011-
  - Gaia International Festival, 5/16/2011-
  - Get Greener!, 12/09/2011-
  - Green is the New Red, 5/02/2011-
  - Shut Down Indian Point Now, 4/25/2012-
  - Support for Daniel McGowan, 8/17/2010-
  - Support Marie Mason, 5/01/2011-
  - WE ACT for Environmental Justice, 5/15/2012-
  - Zeitgeist Movement, 4/25/2012-